Guruprasad Mulay

(guruprasadmulay.info)

34 Endeavour St, Seven Hills, Sydney 2147 Mobile:(+61)426095826 guruprasadmulay@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Information technology professional with a background in computer application, systems and business analysis. Currently working with Newton's Nerds Australia as a Full Stack Developer. Past work experience includes working as a software developer with A.P. Engineers and another six months with Monash University on a community project. Proficient in all aspects of the software development life cycle including requirement analysis, design, development and production support. Additional background includes intermediate knowledge of Data warehouse and Business Intelligence along with strong interpersonal, analytical and communications skills with an ability to lead a team.

Education:

Masters of Information Technology (Professional) / Masters of Business Information Systems (Professional)

Monash University Caulfield, Melbourne 2014-2016

Bachelors of Information Technology

Pune University Pune, India 2010-2013

Certifications:

- JavaScript for Web Designers (Lynda.com)
- Learning Git and GitHub (Lynda.com)
- Learning GIT and GitHub (Lynda.com)

Academic Projects:

Calorie Calculator (Android Application): The Calorie Calculator can be used to estimate consumed calories and burnt on each day.

• Technology: REST services, SQLite, Android Studio

Connect Homeless People(let-connect.tk): Let's Connect is a mobile website that connects people who are homeless or at risk of homelessness with essential services such as shelter, food, clothing and health care.

• Technology: PHP, WordPress, phpMyAdmin (MySQL), JavaScript, Bootstrap.

Experience:

Full Stack Developer Newton's IT:

Aug 2016 - Current

• Support current systems.

- Presenting ideas for system improvements.
- Working closely with product owner and scrum master.
- Creating company standards for coding and version control.
- Writing clean, fast code to a high standard, in a timely and scalable way.
- Troubleshooting, testing and maintaining the core product software and databases.
- Maintaining the systems once they are up and running.
- Maintaining technical documentation.
- Provide training for new systems.
- Technology
 - o PHP, MySQL, Apache, JavaScript, JQuery, Node JS, Doctrine, WordPress, Magneto, Git, python, selenium, PHP Unit, Zend, Apache

Software Developer

A.P. Engineers:

June 2013 to July 2014

- Working closely with analysts, designers and staff.
- Producing detailed specifications and writing the code.
- Testing the product in controlled, real situations before going live.
- Preparation of training manuals for users.
- Features:
 - o Based on the requirements which calculated exact measures of canal designs used for irrigation design and planning.
- Technology
 - o C#.NET, MS Access, WPF

Space Auditor- Monash University

August 2015 and March 2016

- Auditing the usage of space.
- Reporting the usage to higher authorities.

Oriental Tea House

June 2015 to July 2016

- Greet customers, provide excellent customer services that promote satisfaction.
- Make recommendations or share additional information upon request.

Activities:

- Social Worker Swa Roopwardhinee (Team Leader, mentor, teacher) 2007-2014
- Organized technical competition and industrial visits in Pune University.

Technical Skills

- **Programming languages:** Java, C/C++, .net, VB, C#, PHP, Python, JavaScript
- Frameworks: .Net MVC, ASP.Net MVC, Boot Strap, Zend.
- Operating Systems: Ubuntu, Microsoft Windows, Mac, Google Android, Linux
- Web development: JSP, XML, jQuery, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, JSON, JavaScript, REST, Express JS, React
- Applications: Eclipse, Android Studio, SAP, NetBeans, Visual Studio, PhpStorm, PyCharm, Tableau
- **Integration Tools:** Bamboo, Travis
- Databases: MySQL, Oracle, Data Ware house
- Server: Glassfish, Apache2

References:

Available on request.